Previously on the show.
上集說到
Wolffy also attended the farewell party organized
灰太狼也來參加 小精靈們舉辦的歡送會
But his scheme failed.
但詭計以失敗告終
Amid the farewell fireworks the seven colored beans lit,
在七色精靈的送別煙花中
the goats headed towards a new destination.
小羊朝著新的目的地進發
What new challenges are they going to face?
他們將面對怎樣的新挑戰呢？
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Balloon City Amid The Storm."
《奇幻天空島之》
The weather doesn’t look good today.
今天的天氣不太好啊
I think a storm is coming. Should we find a place to take shelter?
感覺會有暴雨 我們需要找個地方躲避一下嗎？
But the radar indicates that our buddy is right ahead.
可是，雷達上顯示 我們的伙伴就在前面
Let's just hurry over.
我們還是抓緊時間過去吧
Hello, little goats.
小羊們
Why is it Wolffy again?
怎麼又是灰太狼？
You can't escape this time.
這次你們逃不掉了
Let me deal with Wolffy.
不如讓我來對付灰太狼吧
Let’s dance, Wolffy.
來跳舞吧，灰太狼
I will be fine as long as I put the headphones on.
只要戴上耳機就沒問題了
Wolffy.
灰太狼
Oh, why am I dancing? Wolffy, help me. I want to stop.
怎麼跳起來了？ 灰太狼，快幫我停下來
Oh no, not again!
怎麼又是這樣？
Tibbie, you are awesome.
美羊羊好厲害
You flatter me...
哪裡…
Why do I feel like Magic Train is moving?
怎麼感覺嘻哈號動起來了？
Oh no, it’s the storm.
是風暴！
We'll be sucked into it.
要被吸進去了
Why am I also sucked into it?
怎麼連我也被吸進去了？
We can't let this continue. We have to break through it.
這樣子下去不是辦法 我們得衝出去才行
Look. There's light on this side.
你們快看，這邊有光
That should be the way out.
就是那邊了
Phew! Guys, are you all right?
大家沒事吧？
I'm fine.
沒事
Weslie, look.
喜羊羊，你看
There's a city in the middle of the storm.
在風暴裡面居然有個城市
That must be where our buddy is.
我們的伙伴一定就在那裡
Let’s go there now.
我們快去吧
Oh, Weslie, Tibbie, come out now!
喜羊羊、美羊羊，快出來
Look, there are balloons everywhere.
你們看，這裡都是氣球
It's such a colorful and beautiful place.
這裡色彩繽紛，好漂亮
Wow, even the ground is soft.
連地面都是軟的
These flowers are all made of balloons.
這些花草都是氣球
Weslie.
喜羊羊
Look, these balloon flowers are so beautiful.
你看，這些氣球花多好看
Hey!
喂
Why did you pick me up?
拿我起來是有什麼事嗎？
Nothing...
沒事…
You're odd.
奇怪
I didn’t expect the citizens to be balloons too.
沒想到這裡連居民也是氣球
Oh no, this is terrible. Guys, come check this out.
唉呀，糟了，大家快過來看
-What is it? -Look.
-怎麼了？ -你們看
-Sparky?
-沸羊羊？
This isn’t the only wanted notice. It's posted everywhere.
不僅這裡有，那邊都貼滿了
Why is Sparky wanted?
沸羊羊怎麼被通緝了？
Weslie, what should we do now?
現在怎麼辦呀？喜羊羊
Let’s go back first.
我們先回去
It'll be easier to find him using the Magic Train.
用嘻哈號來找會容易一些
Sir, we suspect that Sparky is hiding inside this unidentified flying object.
報告，我們懷疑沸羊羊 就躲在這個不明飛行物裡面
Let’s go in and search immediately then.
那我們趕緊進去搜查吧
They're trying to arrest Sparky?
他們要捉沸羊羊？
Why do they look so familiar?
他們怎麼這麼眼熟呢？
White hair, horns on their heads.
白色的毛，頭上有角
I got it. They are Sparky’s fellow mates.
我知道了，他們是沸羊羊的同伴
Hurry, take them back now.
快，快把他們帶回去
Oh no, run!
快逃啊
Stop!
別跑
Wolnie, son, where are you two?
紅紅、兒子，你們在哪啊？
It's a dead end. What should we do?
沒路了，怎麼辦？
There's a gap between the balloon walls. Let’s hide inside.
這些氣球牆後面有縫隙 我們快躲進去吧
Oh no, I’m stuck.
我被卡住了
How come they've disappeared? Let’s split up and find them.
怎麼不見了？我們分頭去找
Yes, sir.
是
The soldiers left.
那些士兵都走了
Weslie? How come you guys are here?
喜羊羊，你們怎麼會在這裡？
Sparky!
沸羊羊！
Guys.
大家
-Sparky! -Are you guys all right?
-沸羊羊 -你們沒事吧？
There's a storm outside. How did you get in?
外面都是風暴你們是怎麼進來的？
Calm down, Sparky. The new Magic Train brought us here.
你冷靜一點，沸羊羊 我們是開著新嘻哈號一路找過來的
The new Magic Train?
新嘻哈號？
Yes, the new Magic Train was constructed by a mechanical expert
沒錯，新的嘻哈號是我在塔塔鎮 認識的一位
whom I met in Tower Town.
機械大師幫我弄的
That is wonderful. With a new Magic Train...
那太好了，有了新嘻哈號…
He isn’t listening to me at all.
根本沒聽我說
I think I hear Sparky's voice from there. Let’s go check it out.
那邊好像有沸羊羊的聲音 我們去看看
Let’s leave quickly. Otherwise, they'll take me back to General Balloon.
我們快走 不然他們就會把我帶回球將軍那裡的
-Wait for me! -Where're we going?
-等等我 -我們去哪？
To look for the Magic Train of course.
當然是去找嘻哈號了
They would surely send a big flying object like the Magic Train
他們看到嘻哈號這種大型飛行器
to the dangerous goods warehouse.
那就一定會把它送到危險物品倉庫
We have to stop them before it gets there.
我們要在送進倉庫之前截住他們
But Sparky, why do they want to arrest you?
可是沸羊羊，他們為什麼要捉你啊？
It's a long story.
說來話長
After the explosion that day,
那一天爆炸之後
I was pushed towards this storm.
我就飛向了這個風暴
What is this place?
這裡是？
Oh, he has horns.
他有角！
Wait.
等一下
Don’t move.
別動
The balloons are afraid of sharp things.
這裡的氣球都很害怕尖的東西
The soldiers surrounded me immediately.
所以馬上就有士兵把我給圍起來了
Everybody, don’t be afraid.
大家不用怕
My horns are rounded. Look, they aren’t dangerous.
我這角是圓的，看，沒什麼危險
Oh, that is so scary! He poked the tree.
好可怕啊，他在戳樹
No wonder they also want to arrest us. It's because of these horns.
怪不得他們也在抓我們 原來是因為這個角
All clear. Let’s go.
沒人了，我們快走吧
Sparky.
沸羊羊
What? Run!
快跑
Stop running.
別跑
They're chasing us. What should we do?
他們追過來了，怎麼辦？
Let’s hide inside the rubbish bin. What?
我們趕快躲進垃圾箱裡吧
What? Where did they go?
咦？人呢？
Let’s check over there.
我們去那邊看看吧
Why are you here?
你為什麼會在這裡？
How dare you ask me that?
你還好意思提這個？
Oh no, why are we sucked into it as well?
怎麼連我們也被吸進去了？
If not for you guys,
要不是因為你們
my family and I wouldn’t have ended up in this strange place.
我們一家才不會掉進 這個奇怪的地方呢
When I was looking for Sirius to leave this place,
正當我想找回天狼號離開這裡的時候
a group of balloon soldiers appeared.
一群氣球士兵就出現了
-Just like that. -Look, it is that wolf.
-就這樣 -看，就是那隻狼
-I became wanted for no reason. -Take him back.
-我莫名其妙地被這群氣球通緝了 -帶他回去
What… What's going on?
怎…怎麼了？為什麼要…
-Why are you chasing after me? -Stop...
-追我… -別跑
Stop!
站住
I wonder how Wolnie and Willie are doing now.
也不知道紅紅和小灰灰現在怎麼樣了
Where can I find them?
我要上哪去找他們啊？
I suppose Sirius has also been taken
你的天狼號估計也是會被氣球們
to the dangerous goods warehouse by those balloons.
帶到危險物品倉庫裡面去的
Dangerous goods warehouse? How dangerous can that be?
危險物品倉庫？那得多危險啊？
Wolffy, calm down.
灰太狼，你冷靜一點
Let’s get the Magic Train and Sirius back together.
我們一起去把嘻哈號和天狼號奪回來
What are we waiting for then? We...
那還等什麼呀？我們…
-Stop! -Run!
-別跑 -快跑
It’s Sparky and that grey fellow.
是沸羊羊和那隻灰色的傢伙
Capture them now.
快抓住他們
Intercept Sparky and that grey fellow!
快截住沸羊羊和那隻灰色的傢伙
Look. Magic Train is right there.
你們看，嘻哈號就在那邊
Where is Sirius then?
那我的天狼號呢？
I have no idea either.
我也不知道啊
What?
什麼？
I’ll take another route. Nothing goes well when I'm with you.
我走另外的路，跟著你們沒有好事
We've finally caught you.
總算抓到你了
Wolffy disappeared right after we turned around.
這灰太狼，拐個彎就不見人影了
I hope he didn't get caught.
希望他別被抓了吧
Move it. Split into two teams and surround them from both sides.
跑起來，再分一隊人從右邊包抄
-They can't escape then. -Yes, sir.
-這樣他們就跑不掉了 -是
What is going on? Why has Wolffy suddenly become the balloons' leader?
怎麼回事？為什麼突然 灰太狼就成了氣球們的首領了？
Friends, I'm really trying to help you capture the goats.
朋友，我是真心想幫你們捉羊的
Can you untie me first?
先幫我鬆綁吧
No way. You are wanted by us.
當然不行，你可是我們要通緝的人
They won't be able to escape.
他們跑不掉了
I'll divert them.
我來引開他們
Get on the Magic Train.
你們趁機上嘻哈號
Hey, come catch me.
來捉我呀
Let's get on the Magic Train now.
我們趕快上嘻哈號
Stop!
站住
Don't run!
你跑不掉了
Sparky, come aboard now.
沸羊羊，快上來
Don't let them get away. Toss me over there now.
不能讓他們走，快送我過去
All right.
好
Why didn't you untie me before tossing me?
怎麼不先鬆綁再扔啊
We can finally leave this place.
終於可以離開這裡了
Let's go!
我們衝啊
The storm is too powerful. We can't break through at all.
這個風暴太強了，根本衝不出去啊
General Balloon, they're back.
報告球將軍，他們回來了
General Balloon.
球將軍
Sparky... are you injured?
沸羊羊，你沒受傷吧？
I told you, you wouldn't be able to break through. You never listen to me.
我都說了衝不出去的，你總是不聽
You forced me to post posters everywhere to bring you home.
還要我到處貼通知找你回家
This isn't a wanted notice but a missing person notice?
這不是通緝令，只是尋人啟事
Yes. Sparky is my good friend. Why would I want him arrested?
是啊，沸羊羊是我的好朋友 我為什麼要通緝他呢？
He didn't cause a commotion when he first got here?
可是他剛來這裡的時候 不是造成了大混亂嗎？
He did cause a commotion when he first came to Balloon City.
他剛來我們氣球城那會兒 的確鬧出了很大的動靜
I really won't harm you.
我真的不會傷害你們的
Don't move.
別動
Help! There's a child deflating.
救命啊！有個孩子漏氣了
Help!
救命啊
-Mom. -My child.
-媽媽 -孩子
General Balloon, you're here.
球將軍，你來了
Are you the one? What is your name?
就是你，你叫什麼名字？
Sparky.
沸羊羊
Hey. Way to go!
好樣的
Sparky, I saw your heroic act just now.
剛才你救人的英姿我都看見了
From now on, you are a good friend of Balloon City.
之後，你就是我們氣球城的好朋友了
-I see.
原來是這樣啊
I didn't expect your friends to misunderstand.
沒想到讓你的朋友們誤會了
Come. Since your friends are here,
來，既然沸羊羊你的朋友來了
let's go back and celebrate with a feast.
我們回去吃頓好的慶祝一下吧
Oh, there's delicious food. Let's go!
有好吃的，我們快去吧
You ended up getting caught too.
最終你們不也是一樣被捉住了
Are you friends with them?
你和他們是朋友嗎？
No, no, no... I don't know them at all.
不…我跟他們一點都不熟
Okay, that's great. Take him to prison.
這就好，帶他去地牢
I'm a good guy. Why am I going to prison? Wait...
我是好人啊，為什麼要去地牢啊？ 等等…
TO BE CONTINUED 2760 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
（未完待續 距離啟航還剩2760天）